#### Contact

+905321733864 (Mobile) hamza.sari@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/hamzasari (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

SharePoint

C#

Java

# Languages

English (Professional Working)
Turkish (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

PSM I (Professional Scrum Master I)

# Hamza SARI

Senior Software Developer at Digiturk Istanbul

# Summary

Experienced Full Stack Senior Software Engineer with 11+ years of extensive experience in the software, telecommunication and banking industries. Strong arts and design professional skilled in front-end (React, ReactNative, ...) and backend development NodeJS, Python, .NetCore, MS SharePoint, C#, Java and many programming languages, Databases, Servers, MVC, Web API, Restful Services, WCF and many MS and Open Source Tools.

# Experience

### Digiturk

Senior Software Developer / Front End Developer July 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month) İstanbul, Türkiye

- istaribai, raikiyo
- Front end development using React, React Native and React Native Web with monorepo to use same code source for many platforms such as Web, Android, Android TV, IOS, Apple TV, Smart TVs(Samsung Tizen, LG WebOS, ...), Electron, Xbox, ...
- Creating front end framework for other developers, using React Native.
- Lecturing new recruits on web and front end technologies.
- Teaching concepts to other team members and review codes with pair programming using remote tools.

#### HrGlob

Full Stack Senior Developer and Team Leader December 2019 - June 2020 (7 months) İstanbul, Türkiye

- Creating hiring web sites and processes for customer companies, using Python, Django, Java, Spring, Vue.JS, JQuery, custom templates from ThemeForest, ...
- Leading and supporting team members about technical topics.
- Analyzing customer expectations and creating related analyze documents.
- Creating technical documents about products and development processes.
- Lecturing new recruits on software development, web technologies, ...

• Creating and lecturing SDLC flows.

Turkcell Technology Research and Development Senior Developer March 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 10 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

- Creating internal flows on custom developed BPM tool using .NET, .NET
   Core, JQuery, Bootstrap, React, ...
- Creating animated contents for large screen billboards, using web technologies.
- Lecturing and supporting new recruits, on Microsoft Sharepoint, web technologies, front end development, custom developed BPM tool for the company, ...
- Creating touch screen billboard applications about field data for employees to monitor real time data about company.
- Supporting AI team and creating web interfaces for developed AI projects.
- Supporting all Microsoft SharePoint projects and developing applications on Microsoft Sharepoint.
- Supporting SharePoint transformation project to find alternatives for specific areas that cannot use or not want to use SharePoint.
- · Creating custom CMS projects, using .NET Core and React.

# Türkiye Finans Katılım Bankası

Full Stack Senior Software Developer and SharePoint Specialist/ Architect/Developer

June 2013 - March 2018 (4 years 10 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

- Need analysis, Project management, Maintenance and support, using .NET, Microsoft SharePoint and front end web technologies.
- Maintaining Corporate Site and other web sites of Company.
- Maintaining Intranet Site and other SharePoint Farms of Company.
- New SharePoint based external site projects (Micro sites of Company).
- Document Center application with customized and improved search on SharePoint 2013 for departments in headquarters and employees in branches.
- HR Applications on SharePoint 2013 (such as overtime, performance, suggest cv, phone book, etc...).
- User Guides application of Company on SharePoint 2013.
- Desktop applications that are used by managers and higher level management for reporting of many systems.

• SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle) Documentation Automation and Expanded Scrum Tracking project according to BRSA(Banking Regulation and Supervision Agency(BDDK)) Audit Rules.

#### Simternet

Senior Software Developer and SharePoint Specialist January 2013 - May 2013 (5 months)

- Custom SharePoint development for Corporate Companies for specific and general needs.
- Installing and managing SharePoint Farms.
- Installing Windows and SharePoint patches.
- Administration jobs and configurations for SharePoint Farms(Active Directory, MSSQL Server).
- Solving problems and development for new requests from customers.

# **BSH Home Appliances**

**Sharepoint Specialist** 

March 2012 - January 2013 (11 months)

- Running the SharePoint farms on all over the world that all company employees are using, except China and Australia.
- · Installing Windows and SharePoint patches.
- Installing new features / extensions with installation guides from Service Management Department.
- Monitoring and managing SharePoint Farm DB Servers and DBs.
- Backup(Snapshot) / Restore processes with using NetApp tools.
- Solving User Profile, Alerts and Search issues.
- Storage optimization and management, (New DBs, LUNs on filers, extension of storage structure).
- Monitoring and managing Virtual Machines and IIS Performance issues.
- · Solving user problem tickets.
- Providing administrative and technical support for local ITs.

#### Veripark

Software Development Specialist

March 2010 - March 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Worked as an outsource on Custom Development of MS Sharepoint 2007 and 2010 projects for Turkcell.

 New external and internal corporate business management softwares were developed.

- Maintenance and fixing bugs for existing projects.
- Installation and customization Microsoft SharePoint 2010 and Microsoft SharePoint 2007 for custom projects.
- Integration new or existing projects with other existing projects.
- Integrating projects with GSM Operator services.
- · Instant support for all projects.
- Administrative and technical support to IT Operation Team in Turkcell for SharePoint installations or other SharePoint related needs.

#### Onur Yazılım

Software Development Specialist June 2007 - March 2010 (2 years 10 months)

Web application development with open source languages(such as PHP, Java, JSP, ...).

Dokuz Eylul University Student 2004 - 2009 (5 years)

After the first year (English preparatory class), I worked for Onur Yazılım and Vestel when I was student at Dokuz Eylul University.

#### Vestel

Software Development Specialist March 2008 - May 2008 (3 months)

Remote Access Production Progress with PDAs

• An embedded system, designed and developed for PDAs that can be related and integrated to Notebook PC production machines. Controllers of production can track whole production progress from this system.

# Education

Dokuz Eylül Üniversitesi Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science And Engineering · (2005 - 2009)